<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata xml:lang="en">
    <Esri>
        <CreaDate>20250628</CreaDate>
        <CreaTime>14094400</CreaTime>
        <ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat>
        <SyncOnce>TRUE</SyncOnce>
        <ModDate>20250629</ModDate>
        <ModTime>120000</ModTime>
    </Esri>
    <tool name="LoadRASTerrain" displayname="Load HEC-RAS Terrain" toolboxalias="RASCommander">
        <summary>Loads terrain layers defined in a HEC-RAS project's .rasmap file into the current map.</summary>
        <arcToolboxHelpPath>toolboxes\RAS Commander.pyt</arcToolboxHelpPath>
        <parameters>
            <param name="in_ras_project" displayname="HEC-RAS Project File (*.prj)" datatype="File" direction="Input" expression="in_ras_project" type="Required">
                <dialogReference>Select the HEC-RAS project file (*.prj). The tool will automatically find the associated .rasmap file in the same directory.</dialogReference>
            </param>
            <param name="import_all" displayname="Import All Terrains" datatype="Boolean" direction="Input" expression="import_all" type="Optional">
                <dialogReference>Check this box to import all terrain layers found in the project. When checked, the terrain selection list will be disabled.</dialogReference>
            </param>
            <param name="terrains_to_load" displayname="Terrains to Load" datatype="String" direction="Input" expression="terrains_to_load" type="Optional">
                <dialogReference>Select specific terrain layers to load. This list is populated from the terrains found in the .rasmap file. Disabled when 'Import All Terrains' is checked.</dialogReference>
            </param>
        </parameters>
    </tool>
    <dataIdInfo>
        <idCitation>
            <resTitle>Load HEC-RAS Terrain</resTitle>
        </idCitation>
        <idAbs>This tool reads terrain layer definitions from a HEC-RAS project's .rasmap file and loads the associated VRT (Virtual Raster) files into ArcGIS Pro.

IMPORTANT LIMITATIONS:
• This tool loads the underlying terrain TIFFs as a VRT with the priority from HEC-RAS in place
• It does NOT include terrain modifications done as vector terrain modifications in RAS Mapper
• Only the base terrain raster data will be loaded
• If your HEC-RAS model includes vector terrain modifications (breaklines, high ground, etc.), those modifications will not be reflected in the loaded terrain

The tool will:
1. Read the .rasmap file associated with your HEC-RAS project
2. Find all terrain layers defined in the project
3. Load the corresponding VRT files that reference the underlying TIFF files
4. Apply the layer priority as defined in HEC-RAS

Select individual terrains or use "Import All Terrains" to load all available terrain layers.</idAbs>
        <idPurp>To load HEC-RAS terrain layers into ArcGIS Pro for visualization. Note that only base terrain VRT files are loaded - vector terrain modifications from RAS Mapper are NOT included.</idPurp>
        <searchKeys>
            <keyword>HEC-RAS</keyword>
            <keyword>Terrain</keyword>
            <keyword>VRT</keyword>
            <keyword>Raster</keyword>
            <keyword>DEM</keyword>
            <keyword>Elevation</keyword>
        </searchKeys>
    </dataIdInfo>
</metadata>
