<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<metadata xml:lang="en">
	<Esri>
		<CreaDate>20250629</CreaDate>
		<CreaTime>10124400</CreaTime>
		<ArcGISFormat>1.0</ArcGISFormat>
		<SyncOnce>TRUE</SyncOnce>
		<ModDate>20250629</ModDate>
		<ModTime>120000</ModTime>
	</Esri>
	<tool name="LoadHECRAS2DResults" displayname="Load HEC-RAS 2D Results Summary Layers" toolboxalias="RASCommander">
		<summary>Extracts 2D results summary data from a HEC-RAS HDF file including maximum water surface elevation and face velocities.</summary>
		<arcToolboxHelpPath>toolboxes\RAS Commander.pyt</arcToolboxHelpPath>
		<parameters>
			<param name="input_hdf" displayname="Plan HDF File with Results" datatype="File" direction="Input" expression="input_hdf" type="Required">
				<dialogReference>Select a HEC-RAS plan file (p*.hdf) that contains simulation results. Geometry-only files will not contain the required results data.</dialogReference>
			</param>
			<param name="override_crs" displayname="Override CRS (Optional)" datatype="Spatial Reference" direction="Input" expression="override_crs" type="Optional">
				<dialogReference>Specify a coordinate reference system if it cannot be determined from the HEC-RAS project files. The tool will first attempt to read the CRS from the HDF file or associated .prj files.</dialogReference>
			</param>
			<param name="results_elements" displayname="Results to Load" datatype="String" direction="Input" expression="results_elements" type="Required">
				<dialogReference>Select one or more results types to extract from the HDF file. Each selected result will create a separate output feature class.</dialogReference>
			</param>
		</parameters>
	</tool>
	<dataIdInfo>
		<idCitation>
			<resTitle>Load HEC-RAS 2D Results Summary Layers</resTitle>
		</idCitation>
		<idAbs>This tool extracts summary results data from HEC-RAS plan files (p*.hdf) that contain simulation results.

Available results include:
• Max WSE at Cell Centers - Maximum water surface elevation achieved at each cell center during the simulation, with the time of occurrence
• Max Vel at Cell Faces - Maximum velocity achieved at each cell face during the simulation, with the time of occurrence

Both results types create point feature classes with attributes for the maximum value and the time when it occurred.

IMPORTANT: This tool requires a plan HDF file that contains results data. Geometry-only files will not work.</idAbs>
		<idPurp>To extract and visualize HEC-RAS 2D simulation results in ArcGIS Pro for flood analysis and mapping.</idPurp>
		<searchKeys>
			<keyword>HEC-RAS</keyword>
			<keyword>2D Results</keyword>
			<keyword>Water Surface Elevation</keyword>
			<keyword>Velocity</keyword>
			<keyword>Flood Results</keyword>
			<keyword>Maximum Values</keyword>
		</searchKeys>
	</dataIdInfo>
</metadata>
